if you have less than 10k in your
trading account I'm gonna show you how
to grow that to well over a hundred K
we're gonna go into the differences
between a hundred dollar account a
thousand dollar account at 10k account
and 100k account and how those trade
differently or we jump into it I just
wanted to remind you guys that there's a
big red subscribe button right there
that's gonna give you access to the most
alpha forex training videos available as
soon as they come out all right class is
in session time to learn so the big
question today is how do we trade with
$100 or $1,000 versus 10k and versus
100k I'm gonna show you the common
mistakes that these traders will make
with the different account balances and
I'm gonna show you the differences on
how you actually want to perform and
there are some slight differences
actually you'll be surprised so make
sure you watch that whole video and and
if you do want to skip ahead to your
particular account size I'm gonna put
the times in the description below so
that you can jump ahead to say you know
if you're you don't care about $100
account because you already have 10k
then go ahead jump ahead in the comments
below so $100 you've got your work set
out for you if you actually plan to flip
your account to 100k which I did say in
the title in the intro of this video
rather that's gonna be near impossible
and you're not gonna do it anytime soon
let me be honest with you now so the
biggest issue I see with trading $100
it's very easy to be risking way too
much you're easily gonna blow your
account even with the minimum contract
size say you bet is 0.01 lots on a trade
and you let that go for a little bit
it's gonna make you lose 10 $20 that's a
very common that's 10 or 20 percent of
your trading account so you do that
times and you're gonna blow your entire
account right it's gonna take you a lot
longer to rekindle these losses however
I will say there is one method that you
can use trading with a hundred dollars
that under my rules that I've set for
myself and other triggers tend to follow
- you can actually trade with a low risk
and that is scalping it is very
important that you practice proper risk
management and no matter what the
account size is and I can make another
video going over proper risk management
in more detail later on but the basic
rules that I teach is that you're gonna
want to risk 2% per trade of your total
account size and this doesn't mean you
have $100,000 for example you're gonna
bet one law every single time because
one law is worth $100,000 what it means
is that if you lose you will lose 2% of
your account this means if you have
$1,000 and you lose 2% of your account
you're gonna lose $20 so we need to find
a formula that's going to be able to
make us lose $20 per trade no matter
what doesn't matter how much you're
gonna win doesn't matter what hair it is
doesn't matter anything like this you
lose $20 per loss that's final the
reason I follow such strict rules with
the 2% loss and no matter what is
because this does not allow me to think
I want to act like a robot in a sense
right I do not want any emotional
control over my trades no matter what
and so it doesn't matter if I have a
good feeling about the pair it doesn't
matter if the news is coming out doesn't
matter if multiple timeframes are lining
up anything and I want to always be
consistent consistent actions equal
consistent results using this method
we're actually gonna have to calculate
how far away our stop loss is as a
percentage and for all you know
stop-loss traders click away now you're
gonna need a stop loss in order
my methods the formula is position size
equals the total account size times how
much you want to risk in our case we're
risking 2% and then divided by the
distance to the stop loss as a
percentage so what does this mean this
means if we have $1000 account for
example and we want to risk 2% of our
account and the distance to the stop
loss is say 0.5% that's going to give us
a total contract size of $4,000 u.s.
dollars then we need to convert that to
lots by dividing by $100,000 because
that's what one lot is worth and that
gives us zero point zero for lots and
that is our best size and that will make
us lose $20 if we are wrong a 0.5% stop
loss is very common if you're trading on
the 1-hour candlesticks for example so
to put that in perspective if we're
talking about a hundred dollar account
again and this is why I'm saying it's
near impossible to trade on higher time
frames with a small account is if we do
that same calculation so $100 times to
$200 divided by 0.5 it's gonna give us a
tenth of that so it's not even going to
be point zero one lot which is our
minimum that size so our risk is
actually gonna be double what we want on
top of that you're only gonna have one
order so you can only take profit in
once some people like to take profit
along the way I will teach some methods
where you can take profit along the way
flip side of things look at the 5-minute
I often see trades
are a distance of 0.1% away $100 times 2
divided by 0.1 that's gonna give us a
0.02 lot that's gonna allow us to take 1
profit that's gonna die let's take one
final profit and so we're actually gonna
be able to trade properly
how do we trade small accounts then we
trade on the smaller timeframes and we
scalp our trades so that we can actually
bet more as a position the only other
thing I would like to add here is if you
do have under $1000 this is the one and
only prime that I recommend breaking my
risk 2% maximum rule and I will say you
can bring that up to an absolute maximum
of 5%
just because $100 is very easy to
accumulate you could probably make that
in one day of work so it's not a big
deal but once we're getting over $1,000
that's when some people start to
struggle with money that's when you
actually want to practice the real rules
of treating hmm so I bet you found that
pretty useful eh who would have thought
this guy might actually have good advice
I'm gonna keep dropping these wizardry
bombs of knowledge on you as long as you
click that like button below thousand
dollars this is probably where most of
you guys are sitting around you keep
dumping money into your accounts over
leveraging you might have a good
strategy that works most of the time but
because you're betting too much and
you're not following that secret formula
that I just gave you that you could skip
back to if you missed it and you're
losing your accounts you're slowly going
broke and you're telling yourself I will
start using proper risk management once
I get enough money that's garbage start
doing it add a thousand this is exactly
the mentality I want to get out of your
head thousand dollars counts are very
powerful once you start compounding your
money you're probably working a
full-time job where you can keep piling
on more money so you're gonna be able to
get to 10k in no time if you're trading
properly and you keep adding to your
account what I'm saying is thousand
dollars accounts are the best place to
actually start learning how to trade
properly you not risking too much money
when you are losing and you do have the
ability to
Creed using proper risk management
you're able to trade any style you want
so what you're gonna have to do is
you're gonna have to start thinking of
strategies you're gonna have to start
listening to other people you're gonna
start having to follow the strategies
that I start teaching you in following
videos and you're gonna actually have to
put them to the test and do back testing
and live data collection testing so
you're really just trying to create as
much data as you can so that you can use
that data for when you do get into the
bigger numbers because then you will
know exactly how much you will gain and
lose over a long period of time I can't
stress how important this step is let me
kind of sum that up for you this is what
you're going to do you're going to ask
trade with that thousand dollar account
and from your job you're gonna start
investing ten or twenty percent of your
income into a side account do not trade
with this money until you've created
that data collection of at least thirty
to fifty trades that are showing that
the strategy that you've created is
profitable all right now you're playing
with the big boys you got 10k in your
account you've built that up from saving
up and you do have a proven method the
10k milestone is gonna mean that you're
going to have to start practicing your
discipline and making sure it's very
strict because you do already know that
method that is gonna get you up to 10k
and the actual trading itself is
basically the exact same and because
you're not getting to high enough
numbers where it's gonna change anything
itself but this is where you're
basically going to have to lock in your
mindset you're gonna have to be in full
control over your emotions even when
something is going wrong in your life or
don't trade when something is going
wrong in your life to say it simply
you're gonna trade the exact same as if
you did with a thousand dollar account
the bigger money does not mean you will
trade any differently here
you just think that you will be trading
differently congratulations you've made
it to every traders goal now this is
actually the most amount of money that
I've seen in a trading account and what
I'm gonna be able to say about it is
you're actually gonna be able to work
full time as a trader with this amount
of money below this it's a little bit
iffy and you do need to worry about you
know if you're gonna have a good or a
bad month with this amount of money you
know that you can live off of just the
earnings of your trading there's a few
differences once you get to this level
where you are living full-time off of
your earnings in trading the first is
simply that a larger portion of your
profits are gonna be taking out as
profits before this you've just been
accumulating your account and hopes that
you would get to this point so now that
you're at this point you're gonna be
taking out your money and you could be
investing that in other businesses real
estate or long-term investments such as
a stock market bitcoin bit connect
whatever from the trading side of things
there is two major differences that you
will see the one is that you can create
walls in a sense so this would be where
you place a limit order and then the
price can't actually pass that because
the smaller traders don't have enough
money to fill your order mind you I need
to make this clear this won't work in
the forex market it will only work in
very illiquid pairs or exotic pairs to
some degree and it will work in small
crypto currencies for example you might
be able to do something with Bitcoin
small illiquid markets you're gonna be
able to make these walls another thing
to note is in these same markets where
there's not much volume you're going to
be able to have something called
slippage this is not good I shouldn't
have worded it that way
slippage is not good
slippage is when you place a market
order a certain price say it's at ten
dollars right now and you market enter
and there's not enough orders resting to
fill your market order it's gonna bring
the price up to eleven so now on the end
of your order you're actually playing
paying ten percent more so 10 percent
slippage is ridiculous you'll normally
see one two percent slivers something
much smaller than that even and but
that's something that the major players
do need to worry about so you're gonna
have to monitor these and if you are in
a illiquid market and you place a market
order you could screw your account over
and then not be able to exit at the same
price or anywhere near the same price to
sum that up playing with big money
you're gonna have more options you're
gonna be able to play games against
other big money if you really want to
and you're gonna be able to control the
market a little bit more that being said
there's more difficult things to
understand also you can't be so
aggressive with your orders you have to
be more careful now then I've got a
bonus one for you this is how the bank's
trade
I don't trade this way I don't have the
money this is when you're getting two
well over a hundred million dollars this
is when you can basically control any
market you want in a sense you can put
walls places so that it takes longer for
retail and other banks to fill the
orders and the way that you're gonna be
trading this way which you won't be but
it's important that you understand this
the way that you can trade with this
amount of money is the biggest issue is
getting your orders filled so you're
gonna have to be very creative and
you're gonna have to put your orders and
cents behind major levels or leave
resting orders for years and months and
then this ultimately kind of creates the
same effect where you'll see a level B
hit it'll bounce off it'll come back
it will go just past that level and hit
the rest of the orders fill those and
then bounce up again this is something
that we like to call stop haunts right
and and that's been when basically
somebody puts their stop-loss behind a
level thinking that if it goes past that
level price is gonna reverse it goes
just past wicks backup and that's
basically filling the bank's order so
what they're doing is they're using the
liquidity of your stop-loss so the
selling of your order to fill their
order so they're really just taking
advantage of your stupidity if you guys
watch this far I'm sure you actually
enjoyed this content so please hit that
subscribe button once again another
thing that you can do is scroll down
into the description I've added a
discord link this is just a community
where we can chat things like this I am
throwing a couple signals up there just
whenever I feel like it but it is not a
signals group
[Music]